<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mokomakambo!</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/feeds/ginjera.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/</id><updated>2014-09-04T21:53:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Underpaid? Resign!</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/underpaid.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-04T21:53:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-09-04:mokomakambo/underpaid.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today's post is courtesy of former Avis CEO Robert Townsend's plain speaking memoir of business and career tips &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/Up-Organization-Corporation-Stifling-Strangling/dp/0787987751"&gt;Up the Organization&lt;/a&gt;: How to Stop the Corporation from Stifling People and Strangling Profits. It's a totally irreverent and fun send-up on turning upside down those frustrating bureaucratic environments that many of us have resigned ourselves to. Not just humourous but practical too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And speaking of practical and resigning, that brings us to the topic of the day. Inspired by Townsend's advice, I did something ballsy today. I resigned from work. Sort of. I handed my boss the following letter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="topic"&gt;
&lt;p class="topic-title first"&gt;Letter of Resignation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear (boss),&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I have come to the conclusion that my compensation does not reflect my contributions to the company’s business and culture or the supply and demand situation in Singapore for comparable skills. There is a world of opportunity outside the company. Therefore, I am tendering my resignation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am happy to consider re-employment with the company with improved compensation in either a full time position or as a contractor. So, I intend to re-apply for my position when it is advertised. This will allow the company to compare my candidacy against other applicants in terms of experience, ability, and salary expectations. I think that you will find that I am the best candidate for the challenges ahead in building up the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case I overestimate my contributions and potential, I am also happy to know that for a fact and move on to a new career as a freelancing professional. In which case, I invite you to propose a suitable date for my last day of employment that will allow a smooth handover of my responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do appreciate the experience of working for you the past four years and would like to thank you for coaching me to be a better manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours sincerely,
ginjera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had gotten tired of getting 3-4% annual increments for the past four years and decided to do something about it. I had been thinking about it since reading Townsend's cheeky book. A mid-year review seemed like the best time to do it. I felt a little uncomfortable to broach the topic, and simply said,&amp;quot;(Boss) today's one on one meeting is gonna be a little weird. (Pause) Today, I resign. Sort of. Here. Read this.&amp;quot; The discussion flowed easily after that. The boss didn't take offense and indicated that salary negotiations are fair game. And asked if I had a number in mind. I asked for 20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll find out in 2 weeks' time if this negotiation bears fruit. Either way, this gambit has already paid off for me. I had been putting this off for a while as I fretted about forgoing my performance bonus by leaving the job. I'm happy I plucked up the courage, shoved my doubts aside and took bold action. I think it's better to commit the sin of commission than the sin of omission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious, here's what Townsend has to say about this topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="topic"&gt;
&lt;p class="topic-title first"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underpaid&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some good people become badly underpaid. If you're in this spot, but likeyour work, cheer up; all is not lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resign. Go to the personnel department. Fillin the forms. Apply for your old position. Under &amp;quot;salary objective&amp;quot;, put down what you should be paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your diagnosis is correct, you'll be far and away the best-qualified applicabnt for your old job and cheap at this new price. When I bullied a griping friend into doing this, he ended up with a 30 per cent pay raise, in a company that didn't believe in paying people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If they don't rehire you because of &amp;quot;regulations&amp;quot;, it's time you left the company anyway, because they've got the tail on the front of the dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, irreverent and practical :) Go get a copy and read it. Now.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="negotiation"></category><category term="underpaid"></category></entry><entry><title>Courageous Leadership: Correcting Misguided Decisions</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/correcting-misguided-decisions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-02T22:44:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-09-02:mokomakambo/correcting-misguided-decisions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Another nugget from Bob McGannon's courageous leadership video. This time it's about challenging decisions from the top without being confrontational.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob shares a story about Charles, a project manager in the Army Corps of Engineers, whose project has been canned by superiors in Pentagon. Charles believes that the decision is misguided based on the type of questions he and his peers on the program had been asked in a questionairre on the programme. And sends out an email to try and correct his superiors' assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He basically tells them that: &amp;quot;I understand the nature of the questions you asked. And I understand the nature of what's happening with this project and programme. But if I were in your position, there are some other information I would want to understand as well.&amp;quot; He then lists a few questions that he would have asked and provided the answers. And ends the note with: &amp;quot;I hope you find this useful.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles doesn't ask for anything. But rather he plants the seed of doubt to correct the misguided assumptions of his superiors. What Charles managed to do was put more truth on the table and add perspective to a decision, without challenging directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this simple communication strategy quite inspiring. In the last two years, I have adopted a more direct confrontational style at work when trying to resolve disagreements. Basically I seek to beat the other party into submission by showing up the flaws in their argument. Sometimes publically. I think this is a response to years of being a quiet introvert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Bob is introducing here is a more elegant way to turn a situation around. And this migh tjust come in handy. I expect a capital project at work may be canclled, I susperct, to make the numbers for the year. This would be a misguided decision in my opinion and detrimental to the morale of the organisation. If it does happen, I'll try to do a 'Charles'.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="leadership"></category></entry><entry><title>Courageous Leadership: How to Say 'No'</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/how-to-say-no.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-09-02T22:24:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-09-02:mokomakambo/how-to-say-no.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've been watching this Lynda.com &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lynda.com/Business-Business-Skills-tutorials/Developing-Intelligent-Disobedience/137908-2.html"&gt;video tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on the topic of courageous leadership. I like the instructor, Bob McGannon; he's energetic, articulates clearly, and has some convincing ideas. One of these ideas concerns a creative way to say 'no'. The tip is to get the requestor to say 'no'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, you're running an initiative and someone has an idea that they want to add to your initiative. Say ,&amp;quot;Yes, and... that will probably cost us another six hundred and fifty thousand dollars. Do &lt;strong&gt;you&lt;/strong&gt; have that in your budget?&amp;quot; They then say 'no' and you can engage in a conversation about their 'no' and how we're gonna get the money to do this great idea. Haha, nice piece of verbal &lt;em&gt;tai-chi&lt;/em&gt; there :) I have to try this at work.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="leadership"></category></entry><entry><title>Searching bash history with ctrl-R</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/bash-history-ctrl-R.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-20T21:53:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-08-20:mokomakambo/bash-history-ctrl-R.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, bash is cool. A couple of days ago I discovered a simple way to search through bash history by piping the &lt;cite&gt;history&lt;/cite&gt; command through &lt;cite&gt;grep&lt;/cite&gt; for a favourite old command and then follow through with a copy-n-paste. Turns out there's an even simpler way to achieve that. Bash has a built in search function!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply press &lt;cite&gt;ctrl-R&lt;/cite&gt; and start typing the first characters of that command you're looking for. Bash will start matching it with the most recent occurence. Pressing &lt;cite&gt;ctrl-R&lt;/cite&gt; again and bash will scroll backwards to the next most recent one. When you find it, press &lt;cite&gt;Enter&lt;/cite&gt; to re-execute that command or use left- or right-arrow keys to start editing the command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out this &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-use-bash-history-commands-and-expansions-on-a-linux-vps"&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; courtesy of the folks at Digital Ocean for the full dirt on bash history features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very. Very. Cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bash"></category></entry><entry><title>Searching bash history</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/bash-history.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-16T21:53:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-08-16:mokomakambo/bash-history.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I was helping my better half to download megabytes of image files from an ftp site. She was having trouble because the ftp connection kept breaking and messing up her workflow of right-click and downloading individual files in her browser. I got to show off the power of the command line with &lt;cite&gt;wget&lt;/cite&gt; and its powerful features like &lt;cite&gt;--no-clobber&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;--continue&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;--read-timeout=*seconds*&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;--tries=*number*&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;--recursive&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;--level=*depth*&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;--user=*username*&lt;/cite&gt;, and &lt;cite&gt;password=*password*&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she made the same request a couple of days later, I wanted to retrieve thos &lt;cite&gt;wget&lt;/cite&gt; commands from bash history to avoid retyping them esp. the long ftp urls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out it's pretty simple. Just run history through a grep filter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;history&lt;/span&gt; | grep wget
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;and out comes a list of commands containing &lt;cite&gt;wget&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there it was just a simple cut and paste.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="bash"></category></entry><entry><title>Lexical analysis in pygments</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/pygments-lexer.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-13T21:24:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-08-13:mokomakambo/pygments-lexer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lexicadelicalicious-what?! According to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexical_analysis"&gt;wikipedia, lexical analysis&lt;/a&gt;  is the process of converting a sequence of characters into a sequence of tokens, i.e. meaningful character strings. In the case of pelican, the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pygments.org/docs/lexers/"&gt;pygments&lt;/a&gt; module does this job. In restructured text, a &lt;cite&gt;.. code-blocks::&lt;/cite&gt; directive tells pygments what to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2
3&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;..&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;code-block&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; lexer

   &amp;lt;bunch of code&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trouble is what are the avaiable lexers? Surely there must be a list somewhere. Indeed there is. And we find it at the pygments documentation site. It's a long list. We find languages (&lt;cite&gt;python&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;ruby&lt;/cite&gt;), markup (&lt;cite&gt;css&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;html&lt;/cite&gt;), 'non-source code file types' (&lt;cite&gt;latex&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;yaml&lt;/cite&gt;, &lt;cite&gt;restructuredtext&lt;/cite&gt;) but strangely no &lt;cite&gt;markdown&lt;/cite&gt;. Hmm, I wonder how folks highlight markdown syntax with pygments. Or don't they?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="pygments"></category></entry><entry><title>Colour settings for ls command</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/colour-settings-for-the-ls-command.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-11T17:53:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-08-11:mokomakambo/colour-settings-for-the-ls-command.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use CentOS 6.5 on my personal laptop. For the longest time, I lived with the awful colour defaults for the ls command. Certain directories default to blue text on green background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Awful default directory colours" src="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/images/Awful-default-dir-colour.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Arghh, my eyes! Please sir, it hurts!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me recently that there must be a text file somewhere that I could tweak to make this more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lo and behold, here's the file that does the trick: &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;/etc/DIR_COLORS&lt;/tt&gt;. And there are nice helpful comments, which tell us that we can adjust 3 elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2
3
4
5
6
7
8&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Below are the color init strings for the basic file types. A color init&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# string consists of one or more of the following numeric codes:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Attribute codes:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# 00=none 01=bold 04=underscore 05=blink 07=reverse 08=concealed&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Text color codes:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# 30=black 31=red 32=green 33=yellow 34=blue 35=magenta 36=cyan 37=white&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Background color codes:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# 40=black 41=red 42=green 43=yellow 44=blue 45=magenta 46=cyan 47=white&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scanning through that file, I found the blue (34) on green (42) culprit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;OTHER_WRITABLE 34;42 &lt;span class="c"&gt;# dir that is other-writable (o+w) and not sticky&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than mess around with &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;/etc/DIR_COLORS&lt;/tt&gt;, I made a copy at &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;&lt;span class="pre"&gt;~/.dircolors&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/tt&gt; and changed the settings for OTHER_WRITABLE to 01;35:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure align-center"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bold magenta folders" src="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/images/Ahh-much-better.png" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Ahhh, purple folders... exactly what the optometrist ordered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a full list of available colours, this &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://linux-sxs.org/housekeeping/lscolors.html"&gt;site&lt;/a&gt; gives the full low down.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="ls"></category><category term="bash"></category></entry><entry><title>Inserting images in restructured text</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/inserting-images-in-restructuredtext.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-11T13:03:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-08-11:mokomakambo/inserting-images-in-restructuredtext.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was struggling to figure out how to insert an image into a post. The example from the pelican docs simply rendered as text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;![Alt Text]({filename}/images/han.jpg)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until I realised that the example was for Markdown. I was writing in restructuredtext. The equivalent in restructuredtext is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class="highlighttable"&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="linenos"&gt;&lt;div class="linenodiv"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;1
2&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="code"&gt;&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;..&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="ow"&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;::&lt;/span&gt; {filename}/images/han.jpg
   &lt;span class="nc"&gt;:alt:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;Alt Text&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;So there it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pelican"></category><category term="ReST"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World</title><link href="http://ginjera.github.io/mokomakambo/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-10T23:24:00+08:00</updated><author><name>ginjera</name></author><id>tag:ginjera.github.io,2014-08-10:mokomakambo/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hooray! Got the blog up and running on &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;gh-pages&lt;/a&gt;. My &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; post using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/3.4.0/getting_started.html"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;! There is much to explore in this world of Pelican, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://openalea.gforge.inria.fr/doc/openalea/doc/_build/html/source/sphinx/rest_syntax.html"&gt;reST&lt;/a&gt;, and static hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="pelican"></category></entry></feed>